Tony Schwebach

Tony.Schwebach.developer@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/tonyschwebach/ https://github.com/tonyschwebach https://tonyschwebach.github.io/my-portfolio/index.html

JUNIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Junior software engineer leveraging corporate accounting and finance experience to build better business tools. MERN stack stills gained from the Georgia Institute of Technology Coding Bootcamp. Recognized as employee of the quarter for collaborative leadership, problem solving, and analytical work to automate processes enabling significant growth with limited additional resources.

React.js

MongoDB

HTML5

Python

Express.js

REST APIs & Postman

CSS3 & Bootstrap

Git & Terminal

Node.js

MvSQL

JavaScript & ¡Query

Agile Methods

PROGRAMMING PROJECTS

Roam Group Travel App - https://www.roam-together.com/ Repo: https://bit.ly/roamRepo

2021

- MERN stack app which allows user to invite travel companions, share expenses, and create a checklist for their trip.
- Tools: React, Express, Node, MongoDB, brcypt, json web token, cookies, Google Places API, Bulma

Employee Directory – https://tonyschwebach.github.io/employee-directory/ Repo: http://bit.ly/empDirRepo

2021

- React app which displays employees and their basic contact information. Users can search and sort employees.
- Tools: React, Axios, JavaScript, Bulma CSS, Dynamic Search

Bird Brains Web App - https://bird-brains.herokuapp.com/ Repo: http://bit.ly/p2bbrepo

2021

- Full-stack app which gamifies bird watching by allowing users to score points based on bird sightings.
- Tools: Express server, Node, mySQL, JawsDB, Heroku, Handlebars, Cloudinary, Slick, Figma, Materialize, MVC design

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Krystal Restaurants LLC - Atlanta, GA

Accounting Manager Aug 2020 – Nov 2020

Supervised 2 direct reports responsible for general ledger, accounts receivable, and fixed assets.

- Created real-time financial statements using SQL and Excel PowerPivot tables connected to the MS Dynamics GP ERP.
- Built Excel model adding insights on payroll expenses for 180 corporate locations.

UniPro Foodservice Inc - Atlanta, GA

Accounting Director

Oct 2018 – Aug 2020

Managed team of 16 staff responsible for all operational accounting and treasury activities of a \$1 Billion company.

- Built workflow KPI dashboards using SQL to identify billing delays and improve daily cash flow by \$1,300,000.
- Used Visual Basic (VBA) to create KPIs in Excel and reduce past due accounts by 2.5%, equating to \$875,000.

Billing Manager Jul 2015 – Oct 2018

Led 4-6 direct reports responsible for invoicing and sales analysis of \$1 Billion of products and services.

- Designed digital workflow using OnBase to reduce document processing time by 30% saving \$60,000 annually.
- Automated invoicing for 20% of orders using EDI 880 invoices allowing 250% growth without additional staff.

UniPro Foodservice Inc - Atlanta, GA

General Ledger Accountant

Jan 2015 - Jul 2015

Staff Accountant responsible for analysis, financial reporting, journal entries, and reconciliations.

- Collaborated with AS400 programmers to whiteboard, test, and deploy account reconciliation program.
- Automated banking transactions improving daily cash flow by \$100,000 and eliminating reconciliation issues.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATION

Full Stack Web Development Certificate, Georgia Institute of Technology – *Atlanta, GA*Certified Management Accountant (cert# 61150), Institute of Management Accountants
Jul 2018

Mar 2021

Master of Business Administration, Southwest Minnesota State University – Marshall, MN

Bachelor of Science (Finance & Management), Southwest Minnesota State University – Marshall, MN

Dec 2014

Dec 2012